<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Atlas Project</title><link href="https://theatlasproject.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://theatlasproject.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://theatlasproject.org/</id><updated>2019-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Discipleship (Lordship)</title><link href="https://theatlasproject.org/Discipleship.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Anonymous</name></author><id>tag:theatlasproject.org,2019-01-01:/Discipleship.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When speaking on and teaching others about what it means to make Jesus Lord, a commonly referenced scripture is Luke 14: 25-27. Jesus clearly states that He has to be #1 in the lives of his disciples with no rivals to his throne. His language is purposefully strong to illustrate the magnitude of how nothing else should remotely compete with Him for the disciples’ love.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When speaking on and teaching others about what it means to make Jesus Lord, a commonly referenced scripture is Luke 14: 25-27. Jesus clearly states that He has to be #1 in the lives of his disciples with no rivals to his throne. His language is purposefully strong to illustrate the magnitude of how nothing else should remotely compete with Him for the disciples’ love. He follows suit by explaining how it is essential that they carry their cross, or in the words of Paul, “nailed the passions and desires of their sinful nature to his cross and crucified them there” (Galatians 5:24). Jesus concludes this thought by saying that those who do not do these things cannot be His disciple. No ifs, ands, or buts about it. No ambiguity. No grey area; just simple Lordship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on in that chapter (verse 33) Jesus states, “So you cannot become my disciple without giving up everything you own.” Again, no blurred lines. He very clearly communicates that He is to be our everything, or nothing to us. The first time I read these scriptures I was bewildered. Jesus saying NO to people!? What happened to just believing and saying a prayer of forgiveness to accept Him into your heart? What happened to everything was going to be OK because God knows my heart? This revolutionized the way I saw God and His Word. I decided I wanted to make Him Lord over my life and follow Him by His terms and not my own; to follow Him, by the way, He was commanding me to follow Him in the Scriptures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, once I made Jesus Lord over my life and began to share with others what the scriptures had to say about being a Christian, I unintentionally compromised the teaching of Jesus. I looked at and taught these verses in Luke 14 as decisions to choose Jesus over whatever might be competing with Him in that moment. So if your mother asks you to lie for her, you choose Jesus’s will over hers. If you have income, you tithe. If you work every Sunday and don’t have the time to make it to church, you search for another job that will enable you to make it to church and foster relationships that will help you to keep fighting for your faith. I explained the concept of making Jesus Lord in verse 33 as being willing to give up anything that may be or become an idol (false god) in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Giving up Everything&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this line of thinking is that Luke 14:33 does not say “be willing” to give up everything you own. It simply says to give everything up, and if not you cannot be His disciple. I unconsciously inserted this qualifying phrase because it did not make sense to me that Jesus would ask EVERYONE to forfeit all they had to be homeless, shirtless, penniless Christians. So, in the spirit of logic, I justified that he had to have meant having the spirit of “if it interferes with me loving and living for you Lord, I will happily give it up.” This was a grave sin on my part, for I was perpetuating the very thing I verbally condemned: compromising/watering down God’s standard. What I once thought was spiritual maturity; I have come to learn is actually God’s standard. I write this now to show how God’s standard does not involve behavior modification, but rather a life of total worship!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Mark 10:17-31, a rich man asked Jesus what he must do to make it to Heaven. We then find out that this is an exceptional man who does not make a habit of sinning. We might even say this man was a righteous and God-fearing man for living a life of obedience. But to Jesus, that wasn’t enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He told the rich man to go and sell everything he had and give the money to the poor “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;THEN &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;come, follow me” (vs. 21, emphasis added). Jesus essentially told this man of righteousness that although he fought not to sin and fought to obey God in his life, he will not be able to follow Jesus UNTIL he sold everything and gave the money to the poor. Jesus looked through the man’s lavish exterior and straight into his heart to see that He wasn’t #1. To Jesus it wasn’t enough to obey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing is that we don’t know how this man handled his money. For instance, despite what many of the lower and middle class think, not all rich people are selfish. There is quite a bit of those with wealth who are very philanthropic; those that have a lot of money and try to bless others with it. Bill Gates is an excellent example. Not only is he one of the wealthiest people in the world, but he is one of the world leaders in philanthropic endeavors and charity donations/work. The rich man that Jesus was challenging could have been a philanthropist. He could have been “making Jesus Lord” over his money by being an active giver, both to his synagogue and to the poor. But Jesus saw that in his heart, the rich man would rather give up God than be poor himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus went on to state twice how difficult it was to get into the Kingdom of God (verses 23-24). Superficially, Jesus exposed the selfishness of a man’s heart to want riches over God. But deeper, Jesus was making a statement; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;it’s not enough to not sin, but it’s about your life worshipping Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This astounded everyone there, for they must have thought (as did I) that fighting with all you have not to live a life of sin _was _worshipping God. But according to Romans 12:1-2, a life of worship is to have everything in your life reflect, honor, and glorify him. This does not mean that you are perfect, for Paul states that there will be a time of perfection to come when we finish this race of life (1Corinthians 13:10). If the time of perfection is yet to come, that means it is not here yet, making us imperfect until that time when Jesus comes back. We, as Christians, don’t fight to be sinless to be perfect, but rather we obey God because He has already saved us. It is not our efforts (however maximal they may be) that make us holy, but rather the blood of Jesus (Hebrews 13:12). I used to think that as Christians, God was calling us to holiness, and we fought toward that holiness by not sinning and worshipping him. But it’s the complete opposite. If we have been cleansed by the blood of Jesus through baptism (Romans 6:1-5, 1 Peter 3:20-21, Colossians 2:12, and 1John 5:6), then we are already made holy! BECAUSE we are now holy through His blood, we must shun sin (1Thessalonians 4:3). If we have indeed died to sin at baptism, how can we continue to live in it? (Romans 6:2). For why would someone who has been scrubbed cleaned and dressed in pure white play in the mud?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when Jesus told his disciples how hard it was to enter the Kingdom of God, after the rich man left, none were more confused and possibly discouraged that Peter; “We’ve given up everything to follow you” (Mark 10:28). Peter was one of the very first followers of Christ (Mark 1: 16-18), and he left everything to follow Jesus. He gave up “everything he owned” to be a disciple of Christ (sound familiar). He not only left his livelihood (fisherman), but Peter had a mother-in-law (Matthew 4:14), meaning he was married and possibly had children. Peter literally left his job, wife, children, and all he had to follow Jesus for over 3 years (Can you imagine leaving your family for 3+ years)! For him, it wasn’t just a willingness to give up whatever was competing with his relationship with God, but instead literally giving up everything to God because his life did not belong to himself any longer...it belonged to Jesus! So when Peter heard how it’s not just about _not sinning _and having a willing heart, he may have been dismayed. But Jesus assured him that by giving up everything to Him, Peter will have everything and more in the life to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rich man, one thing (which wasn’t even sin) kept him from Jesus and entering Heaven. We see Jesus teaching this principle of Lordship in Matthew 7:13-23. He exclaims how difficult it is to get into Heaven and how the “road is difficult” (verses 13-14). This is because it’s not just about making Jesus Lord over your actions, but your heart! There are many who have “made Jesus Lord” and have gotten baptized for the forgiveness of their sins and fought to live a life free of sin to honor God and baptized countless others to do the same. These people will not be allowed into the Kingdom of God because He was only Lord over their actions and never their hearts! That’s what makes the road so difficult because it constantly requires deep self-evaluation and sacrifice of anything that is not of worshipping God. Then Jesus goes on to say that you can &lt;strong&gt;identify &lt;/strong&gt;a tree by its fruit, and people by their actions. I use to think this referred to hypocrites who don’t practice what they preach, but it’s clear now that it is not limited to hypocrites. It also is referring to those of us who don’t curse, or get drunk, or commit adultery, or lie, but do listen to music about sin, watch movies with porn and profanity, and do things that are not necessarily sin but are not acts of worship either. They can be &lt;strong&gt;identified &lt;/strong&gt;as those who do all the rights things but whose hearts do not belong to God, and you can tell because their actions show how they are more concerned with not sinning than worshipping God with everything. This thought is continued in verse 21 when he blatantly exclaims how it is not about what you do, but your heart belonging to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something the Israelites never understood. God gave them so many physical reminders for them to obey Him; from tassels on their clothes (Numbers 15:37-40) to the Sabbath (Exodus 31:13) and all the law of Moses. But they continued to veer off the path by worshipping other gods because their focus was on trying to obey God’s law instead of going after God’s heart. If they saw how God went through great lengths to get them to realize how much He loved them, maybe the outcome of their journey and history would have been different. But that is why God exalted Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, Judah, and King David. These were not sinless men by far, but rather men who understood that their life was not about being sinless for God’s sake, but rather worshipping Him with who they were. Where the Israelites were focused on behavior modification, these men were focused on their hearts belonging to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jesus was asked what the greatest commandment was, He did not refer to the mission of saving souls (Matthew 28:18-20) or living a life dedicated to not sinning, but rather that we must love God with every bit of heart, soul, strength, and mind, and to love others as we love ourselves (Matthew 22:37-40). After all, if we live a life full of the mission, reading our Bible every day, and devoted to the church, but we miss what it means to love God and others, it would all be for nothing (1 Corinthians 13:1-3). To God it was never about obedience. Obedience is a result of your heart to worship Him with all of who you are. That is why 1John 5:3 doesn’t just say “loving God means keeping his commandments,” because there is more to it! The rest of that verse says, “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AND &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; his commandments are not burdensome” (emphasis added). You can keep His commandments all you want, but if they are a burden for you to do so, then that exposes your heart. It goes beyond behavior modification. If your behavior does not reflect your heart then it is all for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My error before was in thinking that Jesus required me to obey him, and then as I matured in Christ I would grow from the viewpoint of not sinning to my entire life being worship and a living sacrifice. But that is not what the scriptures say. Making Jesus Lord is not about modifying your behavior to reflect his will, but rather our hearts belonging to Him and having that reflected in our behavior. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the standard of Lordship: total worship and not just behavior modification. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Jesus did not tell the rich man to follow Him and give up everything in the process, but rather to follow him only after he first gave up everything. When we teach and help those in the world to repent and make Jesus Lord, we must do it from the standpoint of worship and not solely behavior modification. Giving up everything is essential and not just a possibility. Giving up everything means that your life no longer belongs to you, but Christ, and everything you had belongs to Him now (Galatians 2:20). Because you gave it all up to belong to Him, it must all worship Him. Not most of it, having the rest be neutral. All has to give him glory, for according to Jesus, if we do not give it all up for his glory, we CANNOT be his disciple. And if we are not his disciple by his standard, we cannot have our sins forgiven through baptism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you already have been baptized and made Jesus Lord the best you knew how, but didn’t necessarily understand Lordship to this level, there is no need to fear. For in God’s perfect grace, we are commanded to approach the waters of baptism with a clear conscience, for it is effective when we trust God wholeheartedly (1 Peter 3:21 and Colossians 2:12). In essence, if you approached your baptism with a clear conscience that there was nothing you would hide or keep from Jesus and that your life did not belong to you any longer but Christ, His blood covers you! That is part of the beauty of God’s grace; we don’t have to have it all together and understand everything to approach Him. We need to surrender all, and He will teach us the rest as we go (Matthew 28: 19-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for those who never really made Jesus Lord, search your heart and the Scriptures in prayer to find His will for your life. And a warning to those of you more concerned with setting your life up not to sin instead of understanding what things, INCLUDING SIN, are not worshipping God in your life, for you are on a dangerous path to not giving your heart to God. We are called to strip off EVERYTHING that does not help us run this marathon, not just the sin that makes us trip (Hebrews 12:1). Let us worship God wholeheartedly and give our hearts to Him to have forever!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Resources"></category></entry><entry><title>A Discourse on Friendship</title><link href="https://theatlasproject.org/friendship.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Anonymous</name></author><id>tag:theatlasproject.org,2019-01-01:/friendship.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Evaluate your relationships and decide what degree of influence you want people to have in your life. However, whether someone is an acquaintance, working friend, or a lifelong friend, love them all Christ calls us to. If you want a deeper relationship with someone, you must go after it, for there is value in winning friends.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt; Introduction &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be different perspectives of friendship: some have lifelong friendships with enough trust to protect each other's family, some think they have that type of friendship only for it to be revealed as a house of cards under adversity, and others have never really known anyone they would be comfortable calling a friend. Ecclesiastes 4:7-12 emphasizes the importance of friendships and the value they have in our lives. Studies show that those with meaningful relationships tend to live happier, healthier, and longer lives. I believe this is because God created us to be communal beings; to live with and depend on one another while growing together in this journey of life toward Him (Philippians 1:27).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is not to shame anyone for the state of their friendships, but rather to inspire people to go deeper in their relationships and to bring more understanding on what it might take to start, build, strengthen, and maintain a healthy and godly friendship. Please have your Bible on hand and read each scripture as we go through them together to get the most out of this. All Scriptures will be quoted for the New Living Translation. I was super convicted studying out David and Jonathan's friendship, along with some practicals given in the Scriptures, and I pray that this serves you well too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it's necessary to understand there are different types of relationships. A person in your life can be an acquaintance, someone you have a working relationship/friendship with, or a lifelong friend. While it is not practical for most people in your life to be your BFF, please do not mistake them as being less important. They all serve needed roles to balance and mature us in God's perfect love. And as Christians, we are called to love each other the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Acquaintanceship &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An acquaintance is someone you are familiar with, but there is very little to no trust or expectation in the relationship. This could range from that person you say 'hi' to on the train every day on your way to work whose name you never remember, to that person you sit next to in class who you joke around and have light conversations with accompanied by the occasional life talk. The acquaintances in our lives teach us to love those we may not have an emotional connection prompting us to love. They challenge us to love beyond our feelings and help those in need simply because we share their humanity. There is no explicit (and rarely an implicit) expectation to help in time of need, yet we are called by the Lord to love them as we love ourselves. They are some of the "neighbors" Jesus spoke of in Luke 10:25-37. Without acquaintances, our understanding of God's love and how He directs us to love Him would be severely limited and incomplete. The love that God calls us to stretches beyond only loving those we deem worthy of our love. It's instead a wild, contagious, unfailing love (1 Corinthians 13:7) that binds us together as His creation. God is literally love (1 John 4:7-21) and we were all made in the image of this love (Genesis 1:26). This explains why going out of our way to love someone we may or may not know is so fulfilling. We were meant to love more than those we are close to, so please value the significance of acquaintances in your life. Though you may not really know them, love them genuinely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working Relationships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are working relationships/friendships. Misunderstanding this concept and its significance can often lead to unmet expectations and bitterness. Let's define a working relationship as one that is built in the trenches, allowing two people to love and support one another wholeheartedly while being productive and accomplishing something greater than themselves. When these two people begin to go beyond what is necessary for them to be an efficient team together, such as intimately sharing their lives with one another while working together, it can blossom into a working friendship. Both are beautiful gifts from God, and a working friendship is a joyful blessing. Though these relationships are intimately part of our lives for only a season (weeks to years), it would be a travesty to value them any less than lifelong friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example is Jonathan and his armor-bearer (1 Samuel 14:1-23). If it were not for battle, Jonathan may never have had anything to do with his armor-bearer. But for the sake of the mission at hand, they committed themselves to each other entirely to do whatever it took to reach success. Because of their devotion to God, their trust in one another, and their unified purpose, the two of them changed the fate of an entire battle and saved the lives of thousands of Israelites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be analogous to that study partner you had in school who you grew very close to, that coworker you have deep talks and share your life with every day at lunch, or even that brother or sister in your small group ministry that you are in the trenches with every day to win the world for God and help each other stay faithful. These relationships usually end when the convenience of the relationship (your co-worker changing jobs), or dynamics of the partnership end (study partner graduating or brother/sister changing ministries/small groups).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where it gets tricky, for people are quick to get their feelings hurt when this happens. It can start with "we are not as close as we use to be" and progress into "you don't make time for me anymore." This can lead to bitterness and even hatred. One reason this can happen is due to a mismatch in expectations for the friendship. One person is perfectly fine with it being a working relationship/friendship and moving on when that season of their life has passed, while the other expected the working friendship to progress into a lifelong friendship (a common issue if it is not communicated what they want the relationship to be). The neglected friend can then make the gross mistake of saying that the person never really cared for them in the first place (Proverbs 11:9). This is unfair and not true at all! It would be absurd to say that Jonathan and his armor-bearer didn't care for each other and they were only doing their jobs. In fact, the care and trust they had in each other could hardly be matched, even though that relationship might have ended once they were no longer paired together. Instead of becoming bitter at past working friendships that may no longer be flourishing, be grateful you could experience such a friendship at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's essential to have a sober judgment in your friendships. If you consider someone a lifelong friend but they are not willing to fight for that friendship if it were ever threatened or in jeopardy, your disappointment could lead to bitterness, hatred, and a hardened heart toward that individual and God (if never dealt with). Having a sober mind about these things is a part of guarding your heart (Proverbs 4:23) and emotional maturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count your blessings and value the working relationships/friendships in your life. If it were not for these people, we would not know the joy of accomplishing something with someone we have bled, sweat, and cried with. We would be deficient in knowing how to give ourselves entirely to someone for a cause greater than ourselves. It is my conviction that God uses these relationships to further mature us in this way. So don't be rude and ungrateful by saying, "oh, they are not my real friends". Be grateful and praise God for them in your life, call them a friend, and be a genuine friend to them by being all in. However, having realistic expectations for that relationship so that your own heart will not harden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lifelong Relationships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, one of those working friendships will blossom into a lifelong friendship. Again, this is not a hierarchy in which lifelong friends are at the apex, and acquaintances are at the base. They are all equally necessary and important in our maturation as children of God called to love one another. So, the change from a working friendship to a lifelong friendship is not a step up, but simply a change in dynamics and degree of influence. There are also those rare occasions when there is no prior working friendship, but rather that person becomes a lifelong friend from the start. Please know that neither is more significant than the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few better examples of what a healthy and godly lifelong friendship looks like than David and Jonathan. Their story begins in 1 Samuel 18:1-4 after David kills Goliath. We can see three key characteristics to the start of their friendship. The first is Jonathan loving David as he loved himself, obeying the words of Christ who thousands of years later would command people to LOVE their neighbor as themselves (Matthew 22:39). We see from this that our "neighbor", in the eyes of Christ and Jonathan, can range from a stranger/acquaintance (aforementioned) to a life-long friend. There should not be levels to this love if we are to imitate Christ. He does not love the righteous (those that He calls friends in Romans 5:11) more than the unrighteous (those he calls enemies in James 4:4), and neither should we love our life-long friends more than our acquaintances (we see in John 3:16 and Romans 5:6-8 that Jesus died for both the righteous and the unrighteous, showing his unfailing love for both).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Love &amp;amp; Intentionality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different types of love (agape vs. eros vs. philia vs. storge), and we can love different people in these different ways as God does, but loving differently is not synonymous with having a greater love for them. God had a different relationship with Abraham than He did with Lot, but that does not mean He loved Abraham more. He has no favorites (Colossians 3:25), and neither should we with our love. This is slightly beyond the scope of our study, but this is an excellent discussion to have, and I encourage you to study it out, as will I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then see Jonathan and David made a COMMITMENT to one another. They decided from the beginning what type of relationship they wanted to have, and they committed themselves to that friendship. Often when we have working friendships that have lasted for years, we assume that person will always be there for us. Don't make assumptions; if there is a friend you would like to go deeper with, have an honest conversation with them about the state of your friendship and what it will take to build a stronger and more sustainable one. We see this as common sense in romantic relationships, but we tend to neglect this principle in our friendships? When the dynamics of a working friendship change, it takes love, humility, and intentionality to keep that friend. A first step in being INTENTIONAL is a commitment to one another. If you approach your friend and they are not interested in making such a commitment, don't get salty and pout. Instead, have a thankful heart that you were able to share a special relationship with that person for that season of your life. Again, it takes humility and emotional maturity to learn to let go of relationships in a healthy way. If you are the one that is unwilling to make that commitment and need guidance on how to respond in that conversation, pray for wisdom and don't be afraid to be honest with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also see that Jonathan made the first move. He put his insecurities and pride aside to humble himself and give David, whom he had just made a commitment to, his robe, tunic, sword, bow, and belt. He, the son of the King and future King himself, humbled himself by giving this peasant boy his tokens of royalty and strength, showing how he values their new friendship above these things. He stripped himself of everything that would protect him from or elevate him above David, leaving himself vulnerable and exposed before his new friend. And this show of vulnerability was before David showed any sign of honoring their commitment. It takes a secure and humble person to be that vulnerable, valuing a relationship over the fear of getting hurt (1 John 4:18). Notice David did not do the same thing (he likely had nothing to give). This shows that to Jonathan, his friendship and love for David outweighed the importance of complete reciprocity in their friendship. Jonathan didn't care; he just wanted to do whatever it took to build and keep that friendship. Don't be afraid of showing your friends you care. Make yourself bare before those you want to have as a friend for life, for vulnerability (whether physical or emotional) is the ultimate sign of trust in a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next interaction we see between Jonathan and David is in 1 Samuel 19:1-7. Saul is determined to kill David, but Jonathan defends his friend. He shows he is willing to get his hands dirty to create peace. From this, we learn LOYALTY. In the ongoing conflict between Saul and David, this is the first-time Jonathan aligns himself with David. This illustrates how Jonathan was more concerned with keeping his commitment to his friend than appeasing his father/king. This level of loyalty (or lack thereof) can be exposed when it might be an embarrassment or political suicide to align yourself with your friend at their most publicly humiliating and vulnerable moment. Either you do it anyway because your friendship with them means more to you than the scrutiny and consequence of their association at the time, or you don't do it because in your heart it's not worth it. Either way, it very clearly exposes the friend you are to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened to me with a friend of mine who was a manager. At one meeting, his group began to form an angry mob against him. When tensions were highest, my friend asked me to help him close out the meeting. I had to make a decision; was I to go against this angry mob and support my friend in the midst of the chaos and shouts for his head, or was I to lay low to avoid impending embarrassment and political suicide? I saw the "I don't know what else to do" look he had, and I knew I had an obligation to support my friend no matter the repercussions. Defending him was more important than the possibility of the angry mob shouting to have my head too. He was worth it and always will be. Loyalty will always be valued (Proverbs 3:3 and Proverbs 20:6), and loyalty beyond consequence fosters trust and devotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next interaction between Jonathan and David is throughout 1 Samuel 20. We can see that David is not afraid to be weak in front of Jonathan. David, a fierce warrior, reduced himself to show his friend how he is truly feeling. He doesn't care how it makes him look, but rather trusts his friend in his moment of vulnerability. At times, we can be very good at putting on a mask to conceal from the world our true feelings of insecurity, frustration, and sadness. But friendships can only go as far as there is TRUST. There needs to be trust that you can bare all your weaknesses and dirty laundry without being judged. The quickest way to build trust is to be your real self and watch how they respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan responded with HUMILITY by asking David how he could help. Jonathan did not assume he knew how he should help David, and he did not just listen and say, "I'm sorry to hear that bro." He wanted to make sure he was there for his friend in a way that David would feel supported. At times, we can arrogantly want our friendships to go the way that we want. But it shouldn't be about you or what you want; it's about having the humility to consider someone else as more important than yourself (Philippians 2:3-4). I've had numerous people say to me "for us to be friends, this is what I need from you." Instead of taking an approach that is focused on self, why not follow Jonathan's example and ask in humility "what can I do to love and serve you?" Narcissism extends so deep into our subconscious that the only time many of us hear someone ask us "how may I serve you" is when we go to Chick-fil-a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve your friends. And don't just serve them the way that you want, but find out how they would want to be served (a good book on how to do this practically is The Five Love Languages by Gary Chapman). True consideration is above how you feel. Think of it this way, your friendships should never be an inconvenience to you. Whether it means waking up at 3am to pick them up from the airport or traveling cross country to go to their grandmother's funeral, you make it happen with joy in your heart because they are worth it to you. This level of consideration and humility is what Jonathan demonstrated when he asked his friend how he could help and be there for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout their interactions, we see a theme that Jonathan may have cared more for David than David did for Jonathan. 1 Samuel 20:17 is the 2nd time it is mentioned that "Jonathan loved David as he loved himself", but not once did it say that David loved Jonathan as himself as well. I don't think that's a knock on David's love for Jonathan because that's a high calling to match (although this is the love that Christ called us to, as aforementioned). But rather it shows how that didn't matter to Jonathan. He was not afraid of giving more to David than David could give to him. He didn't need complete reciprocity to give his all to that friendship. All he needed was a commitment from David to have love, humility, and to be intentional in their friendship (hence their recommitment to each other in verse 17). Boundaries are needed in every relationship, but perfect reciprocity will not always exist. The question we must ask ourselves is whether that matters to us or not. There is no right answer, only awareness on where you would like the relationships to be. For Jonathan, he valued David beyond reciprocity (taking the pressure off David to live up to expectations).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their last interaction can be seen in 1 Samuel 23:16-18, at the height of Saul hunting David. Jonathan went out of his way just to encourage David to keep going. He risked his life to simply relay to his friend that he believes in him. Jonathan shows there is nothing he is not willing to do for the benefit of his friend. This ENCOURAGEMENT, something we all need (Hebrews 3:12-13), might have been the very thing that pushed David to keep going and not give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also see that for a 3rd time, they REAFFIRM their commitment to their friendship. It is not a coincidence that in almost every interaction we see in the Scriptures between David and Jonathan, they are reaffirming their commitment to one another. It is important to communicate with your friends what they truly mean to you. It is a form of encouragement that fights against bitterness and pride, helping to build a lasting relationship. This was the last time the two of them would ever see each other again, for Jonathan is killed shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thing worth mentioning is the time that David and Jonathan spent together. Some believe that abundant time needs to be spent between two people for them to build a friendship, and I would like to challenge that notion. It appears that David and Jonathan hardly saw each other, and yet their bond was stronger than ever. Although their time may not have been abundant, it was meaningful and valued. Abundant time is not needed to build a relationship. Still, the time that is spent needs to be protected and equally valued by both parties. This is especially the case if you or your friend's love language is quality time. Again, it's not necessarily the amount of time spent that matters, but the QUALITY of that time. If this is you, please do not put an unrealistic expectation on your friends to have a certain amount of communication with you for your friendship to stand. It is not fair to them, and it ironically fosters working friendships (due to convenience) rather that deepening lifelong friendships. However, communication is essential in working relationships/friendships. So, if a lifelong friend is also a working friend, you would need to talk to them frequently for the sake of the mission at hand. But work mustn't be brought up in every interaction. Otherwise, you both can begin to subconsciously associate that relationship with work only. There must be time to connect, aside from work, to foster that relationship. From David and Jonathan's example, we see that time spent should have nothing to do with the depth of a relationship; we must go deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at their remarkable example, Jonathan and David quintessentially lived out 1 Corinthians 13:4-7. They fought for their relationship under the most extreme circumstances, and their reward was a friend that was closer than a brother (Proverbs 18:24). The major characteristics we explored in their friendship was Jonathan's love for David, the humility Jonathan showed to consider David before himself, both of their willingness to be vulnerable and weak before the other, their intentionality in committing to each other and reaffirming that commitment often, the loyalty Jonathan had for David, Jonathan's desire to serve and encourage his friend at any cost, and the trust they had in each other. These are all character traits that God can use lifelong friends to mature us in personally. Without lifelong friends, we miss lessons in love, vulnerability, commitment, loyalty, encouragement, trust, and consideration. Because of their special place in our hearts, they can influence our character, unlike anyone else (Proverbs 27:17, and 1 Corinthians 15:33). So, value your lifelong friends and don't take them for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, evaluate your relationships and decide what degree of influence you want people to have in your life. However, whether someone is an acquaintance, working friend, or a lifelong friend, love them all to what Christ calls us to. If you want a deeper relationship with someone, you must go after it, for there is value in winning friends (Proverbs 11:30). From what I've seen, a few of the reasons people don't have deep friendships is because of a lack of vulnerability, lack of humility, fear of being hurt (leading to a lack of vulnerability), selfishness (considering others as better than themselves), or they just don't fight to go deep and keep relationships. Don't just let life happen to you; go after the friendships you want, and allow God to mature you in the process. And don't be afraid to get hurt, for without pressure and friction, how would a diamond ever be form or a gemstone ever shaped? This topic goes much deeper, but these are just a few of my thoughts. Below are some practicals that have helped me in my life with my friends. Please feel free to add to this list what you have found helpful, and let's strive to grow together in being better friends, all for God's glory!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PRACTICALS:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a list of the people you want a deeper friendship with. Title it the "worth fighting for" list, and go after those friendships one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an honest conversation about your relationship. Think of anything you may have done to hurt them in the past and sincerely apologize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive them of anything they may have done to hurt you and let it go before you converse with them. Fight for that forgiveness in prayer and allow room in your friendship for them to make mistakes (Ephesians 4:2 and Colossians 3:13). This means stop taking things personally. You must trust that they love you and would never intentionally hurt you. If you cannot accept this in your heart, then your friendship is worth re-evaluating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a commitment to each other (must be mutual).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaffirm that commitment throughout the relationship. This includes not being afraid to show them how much they mean to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be afraid to make the first move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't assume just because you are close with someone it will always be the case. Talk about your friendship and commit to them if you so choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be afraid to be embarrassingly vulnerable with your friends. It goes hand in hand with trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that you are only going to get a few lifelong friends, so don't be overzealous in committing to everyone. Be sober in your judgment of who you want to fight for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for ways to serve your friends the way that they would want to be served. Make it a common part of your friendship. Go out of your way to serve them. They will notice and take it to heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always give them the benefit of the doubt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not rely on your friendship to give you peace and a sense of security. Jonathan could be all that he was to David because he was already secure in God. Let's do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call them to check to see how they are doing (and not just when you want to talk about something specific).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love them the way they best feel love and not just the way that's comfortable to you. (Check out &lt;a href="https://www.5lovelanguages.com/"&gt;The Five Love Languages by Gary Chapman&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pray for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Resources"></category></entry><entry><title>The Engineer's Guide To God</title><link href="https://theatlasproject.org/the-engineers-guide-to-god.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2001-02-26T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2001-02-26T12:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Buddy Brinkley</name></author><id>tag:theatlasproject.org,2001-02-26:/the-engineers-guide-to-god.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want the facts. I want them quickly, concisely and logically expressed. I don't want a lot of fluff in between. Don't waste my time with a lot of symbolism and allegory, and don't bore me with cute stories or emotional testimony. Just give me the bullet points and the details that I really need to know. Oh yeah -- make it short. I prefer the "Cliff Notes" version. So, with that in mind, here goes my contribution to the world...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Note from the Author:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2001 by Buddy Brinkley. Revision 1 Copyright 2002 by Buddy Brinkley. Revision 2 Copyright 2004 by Buddy Brinkley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may copy this document, you may sell it, you may give it away, you may translate it, you may publish it, but you may not change it, you do not own it, and you may not prevent anyone else from copying or distributing it. Please do not clog up anybody's e-mail system with this document. Please do not attach it to any e-mail that says something like, "If you really love Jesus, you'll pass this along to 42 thousand of your closest friends." I really hate that stuff.
You must include this Copyright notice with all copies of this document.
"Scripture taken from the HOLY BIBLE, NEW INTERNATIONAL VERSION. Copyright 1973, 1978, 1984 by International Bible Society. Used by permission of Zondervan Publishing House."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 1:  God Exists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're an engineer, you've most likely got a certain amount of common sense, to which I will now appeal.  Look around. Look at the intricacy and vastness of the universe. Look at the amazing designof your own body. Look at how everything in the universe -- down to the last teensie tiny particle of an atom -- all fits together into an incredibly complex system that has the remarkable ability to actually continue to function for an apparently long period of time. Do you really believe that such an amazing system could just make itself?  We who design the structures, machines, and toys of civilization ought to recognize design when we see it. Of course there's a God. Only a liberal arts major would believe otherwise. Let's move on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, on second thought, let's not move on just yet. Even in Engineering School, we get a few close-minded folks from time to time. This is for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a pile of dirt. Now, take anything else you think you might need, and make a human being. Good luck. Okay, I'll make it easier for you -- just make an amoeba. No, wait a minute; we want to put this on the level of creation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a vacuum...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now make the pile of dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 2:  Why Did God Make All Of This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could make it, wouldn't you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 3:  How to Choose A Religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try mine. It works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I thought seriously about ending this chapter right there. But, let's face it; everybody claims that their religion works. I think there's a certain validity to that claim. Who am I to tell somebody that their religion isn't working for them? But I have a few points to make about Christianity, because I believe it uniquely beats the alternatives. Actually, I believe that Christianity is the fulfillment of Judaism, Hinduism, and Buddhism. I'm not so sure about Islam, since it came after Jesus. I'll let you Islamic guys check into that one. Oops, I'm rambling. Okay, back to the guide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any religion that claims that you can do anything to make yourself "good enough" for God is aiming at a mark that is unreachable. We are just little specks of dust in His universe. Our lives are just little blips in the vastness of time. He is beyond the universe. He is beyond time. What are you going to do to get to His level? I believe that Judaism, Hinduism, and Buddhism came before Christ to show us an ideal that we could not reach. I suspect the same is true of Islam, even though it came later in that timeline. God is beyond time, remember?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible teaches that God stooped down to our level -- He Himself became a man, Jesus Christ, and walked among us. He identified with us, because we could not identify with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've probably heard the term, "Born Again Christian." Here's what it means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can not make yourself into the person that God wants you to be. You can not simply believe the right things, accept the right rules, and live a life that is good enough for God. Many Christians think that's how to live the Christian life. It is not. That's how to be a good Jew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants to remake you. This requires that you give yourself completely to Him. You give up your goals, your dreams, your wants, your needs -- everything. Then, you simply ask Him to make you what He wants you to be. After that, it's His problem to do it. Your part is to keep giving yourself to Him. His problem is to remake you. You can not force Him to do it. You can not make it happen. But, it is what He wants, and only your free will, and your refusal to submit to Him holds Him back. Once you surrender, He will do the rest. Just don't try to do it yourself. That's the biggest mistake that Christians make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have difficulty with not doing it yourself? Many do. Go back to that vacuum in Chapter 1 and try to make dirt. Do you get it now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I’ll spell it out for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t do it. Neither can you make yourself what God wants you to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only God can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 4: So What About that "Sin" Thing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've heard folks talk about a thing called "sin." Here's what it means...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at all the major religions of the world. All of them have rules for living a life that pleases God. Many of these rules look similar as you compare the different religions. Sin is breaking the rules. But, there's a little more to it than that …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its heart, sin is selfishness. Sin is seeking to get what we want for our own selfish enjoyment, typically without much concern for anything or anyone else. Sometimes, we may mask it with a thin veil of self-righteousness or charity, but our motives are still selfish at the core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody is this way until God changes them. That's sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can not come to God in sin. God hates sin. He loves us, but He hates sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does God hate sin? He hates it for the same reason that we hate it. Sin hurts. It does damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the Ten Commandments – Thou shalt not lie, Thou shalt not steal, Thou shalt not kill, etc., etc. We all hate that stuff. Just about every religion has rules against the same basic “sins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most everybody hates sin – particular when it’s done to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture Heaven – life after death.  Most people picture bliss. We picture a place and a state of being that is full of peace, love, and happiness. We picture perfection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t have that kind of Heaven and still have sin. That’s why there is no Heaven here on Earth. And that’s why God hates sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hate it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we can only get rid of sin by being remade by God, but we can't come to God because we're full of sin and He hates sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're doomed, man. Bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 5:  Jesus Died For You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus died on the cross back around 30 AD to take upon Himself the punishment of everybody's sin. That's what the Bible teaches. That's what Jesus taught. That's how you, a person full of sin, can come before God and get remade. That's what Christians mean by "getting saved." Jesus saves us from sin. Oh yeah, by the way, the normal penalty of sin is death, hell, etc., etc. It's best to be
saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ch 6:  Let’s Have A Come To Jesus Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you get it by now. Some of the typical religious jargon that is commonly spoken should now
make a little sense. Let's review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're a sinner. We're all sinners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God hates sin. God loves us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That's a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus has solved the problem. He died to pay the penalty for sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now come to God, and be forgiven of your sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you do that, you must be remade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only God can remake you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can't be reborn into a new life, without dying to your old life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people come to God because they are afraid of dying, or because they want something that they can't get for themselves. That's not how it works. That's selfishness. God's not Santa Claus; He's the ruler of the universe. He does not exist to please us; we exist to please Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all refer to it as "getting right with God," but we don't stop to consider what that means. You're supposed to get right with God. So, you should do it, not for what you can get to please your selfishness, but simply because IT IS RIGHT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Churches are full of people who are still trying to use God to fulfill their selfish desires. They are fooling themselves into a false sense of security that is shallow and baseless. Don't follow them. Follow Jesus. Follow the leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chapter 7:  Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's between you and God Himself. I suggest you talk with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I've got a few tips, so I'll throw 'em out...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a Bible. If you are an engineer, don't waste your time with a King James Version of the Bible. Its language is difficult to read, and we engineers have enough trouble with reading already. It was a great version back in the 1600s, but it's a bit hard to understand now. Also, don't waste your time with anything that claims to be a "paraphrase" version of the Bible. "Paraphrase" is a fancy way of saying, "We translated it, then we reinterpreted it, then we wrote it down." I'd rather interpret it for myself. Just give me the facts, not your opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like two different translations. I like the New International Version, because it is fairly accurate and it is easy to read. I also like the New American Standard Version. It is sometimes more of a literal translation than the NIV, but it's also a little more difficult to read. I use both. Go to a Christian bookstore, and check them out for yourself. Get what works best for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, once you've got a Bible, start studying it. It is God's technical manual for your soul. But, it's kinda big, ain't it? Here's a tip: Start with the Gospel of John. It's in the New Testament -- the part that was written after Jesus lived on earth. Then, skip over a little ways to Romans. The book of John gives you the words of Jesus. Romans gives you the basic tenets of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will read in John all about Jesus' life, His death on the cross, and His resurrection from the dead. Oh yeah, that's the good news. Not only did Jesus die for our sins, He also triumphed over death itself. Sounds impossible, huh? Go back to Chapter 1. Try again to make that dirt in the vacuum. It's impossible. Now, look around. God made everything out of nothing. God has no "impossible." Get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Christian guy named Leonard Ravenhill once said, "Christianity is either supernatural or superficial." So, get used to the fact that God specializes in the impossible. The road ahead of you, once you surrender yourself to Him, is quite amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In John, you will also read about the Holy Spirit. It is by the Spirit that we are remade. John says it a lot better than I can, so check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, read 1 Corinthians 13. In this new life with God, the rules aren't the gig -- they just exist to make you aware that you have a problem. The gig is way beyond the rules. It's all about love. God wants to teach you love. That's a big step for an engineer. Surrender -- God will take care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yikes! Did he really say that? Aren’t churches full of hypocrites? Well, quite truly, many people have had bad experiences with churches. And, many churches are not all that they should be. But, the Bible refers to the church as the “body of Christ.” Each of us is a part of that body. Body parts
are not designed to stand alone. Neither are we. You need other Christians. Other Christians need you. So, go to church. What church? Ask God to lead you to the right church for you. He will do so. Want a more “down to earth” method? Find a Christian in your peer group whom you admire. Go to church with that person. Beware of churches that have their own translations of the Bible, and beware of churches that have scriptures in addition to the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last tip: Christian literature is huge. It's a bit hard to sift through, and new books are added every day. Read the Bible. Don't neglect the Bible to read other stuff. But, it's good to also read other books from time to time. Here are two books that I recommend, both by a man named A.W. Tozer: The Pursuit of God, and The Root of the Righteous. I got a lot out of them. Most likely, you will, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True religion, of whatever flavor, consists primarily of knowing and loving God and serving Him by loving others -- not self-preservation, or self-anything-else. Jesus said, "Now this is Eternal Life: that they may know You, the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom You have sent." God wants you to get to know Him. He wants to be your closest friend. This is the great task of Eternal Life. Once you "get right" with God, your eternity with Him begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you well in this quest for God. The sooner you begin, the less regret that you will have for not starting earlier. So get started. I'm done. Now it's between you and Him. God bless you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it. That's all I've got. I hope it helps. Have a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href="http://www.engineersguidetogod.com/"&gt;engineersguidetogod.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Resources"></category></entry></feed>